Lucas Brown

Pipeline TD

Contact

Address

Orlando, FL, 32825

Phone

(747)-221-4849

E-mail

ImLucasBrown@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/imlucasbrown

Skills

Python

Maya (pymel, cmds, om)

Linux

Rigging

Tech Anim

Pipeline TD/Technical artist with experience in full stack Python development, pipeline backend/tools, rigging, Pixar USD, and motion capture for animation and games. Expandable and easily deployable systems are king. Motivated and excited to work with supervisors, artists, and programmers to create a well oiled, easy to use, CG pipeline.

Work History

2019-09 -2020-12

Pipeline TD

Sunrise Productions, Cape Town

- Lead full stack Python developer on "NXT" (Node Execution Tree).
 A visual, node base, layered, code compositing application.
 Utilized Qt framework. Developed RPC/IPC backend for linear code execution in multiple DCCs.
- Pipeline backend development. CLI tools for asset creation and Python entry points for front end devs to utilize in various user interfaces.
- Pixar USD research and integration

2017-11 -2019-05

Character Rigger

Pretty Simple Games, Paris, France

I developed rigs for characters, props, and vehicles to be used in a mobile game. On the pipeline side I took it upon myself to develop tools and workflows for the development of tools for asset creation/publishing.

On the animation side I developed tools for motion capture retargeting as well as easy QTE (Quick time event) creation and editing inside Maya.

2017-06 -2017-07

Technical Artist

SVAD Productions, Collegedale, TN

- Rigged quadruped creatures for VR experience.
- Refactored legacy pipeline code to support newer versions of Maya.

Education

2013-01 -2017-05

Bachelor of Science: Animation

Southern Adventist University - Collegedale, TN

Awarded "Excellence in Character Technical Direction"